Kobato-chan, you came!
来たわね　小鳩ちゃん
理科は
Where's Rika?
Rika's not here yet!
理科はまだ来てないぞ
Huh? The movie's not here either, then?
それじゃ映画も
Movie preview
Editing (almost done!)
Editing masterfully
Final scene
Re: VFX
Correct.
She messaged me last night
昨日の夜　朝までには必ず凄いのを完成させてみせるというメールがあったのだが
that she'd have a masterpiece done
by this morning come hell or high water...
Wait, don't tell me she
worked through the whole night?
あいつ　まさか昨日から徹夜で
I'll go check on her.
Neighbors Club
Movie Screenings
Chapel Common Room 2
ちょっと見てくる
"Sect Σ"
"Lab-Storage-Room"
Hey, Rika!
おい　理科
あれ　鍵が
It's unlocked?
Rika?
理科
Rika!
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
知らないフリしたって
Yeah, you played dumb
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
もう一歩
I'll walk another step toward your side
君の隣に行こう
I bet I can even reach your hand
その手にだって届きそうさ
"Haganai NEXT"
想像しちゃダメ
It's more than I imagined... every
day's a roller coaster
ジェットコースターな毎日
引き締めて前を向いて
I always barreled ahead with everything I had
いつも駆け抜けたら
ずっと続きはしないね
Our time won't last forever, now will it?
僕らの時間は今しかないから
Now is all we have, so let's make
sure we remember this moment
この瞬間刻みづけよう
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Yeah, you played dumb
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
I'll walk another step toward your side
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
受け止めるように
So I can take your hand
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Yeah, I'm always gazing at the sky
見上げてばかりだって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I'm still drawn to it
憧れてる今も
One more time! I'll reach out
to you as many times as you need
もう一回
何度でも手を伸ばそう
あの星だって届きそうさ
I bet I can even reach that star
"Dismay of I, the Chicken"
They said it's just a cold.
ただの風邪だってさ
Sheesh, she shouldn't worry us like that.
もう心配かけさせないで欲しいわね
Maybe...
すこし…すこしあいつに頼り過ぎていたのかもしれないな
Maybe we've been leaning on her too much.
Yeah.
そうだな
But we can't waste time
thinking about that now.
だが今はそんなことを言っている場合ではない
"Waste time"?!
そんなことって
We'll save the self-reflection for later.
We have to get started now.
反省は後だ
すぐに取りかかるぞ
On what?
取りかかる
The screenings are canceled.
上映会は中止だ
Canceled?!
中止
ちょっと残念ね
It's kind of a shame.
出来ていないのだから仕方ないだろう
It's not finished. We have no choice.
Plus...
それに　最初は七人で見なければ意味がないからな
It's pointless if all seven of
us aren't at the first viewing.
Yozora...
夜空
The Neighbors Club movie
screenings have been canceled.
Cut it out!
こうりゃ 掲示板に悪戯しないでくださいって
No messing around with the bulletin board!
Hasegawa-kun, it's you!
羽瀬川君じゃないですか
Oh, hi, Yusa. I'm not messing with it.
遊佐か　悪戯じゃねえよ
My club's presentation was canceled,
so I'm taking down the posters.
部活の出し物が中止になったから　ポスターの回収をしてるんだ
Please accept my apologies.
これは失礼しました
I know you're not the type of
person to pull pranks, Hasegawa-kun.
確かに羽瀬川君のような人が　迷惑行為などするわけがありませんよね
Sorry, I'm kind of moved.
いや　ちょっと感動して
Usually people don't believe me, or
they just run away before I can explain.
いつもは釈明してもわかってもらえないか
釈明する前に逃げられるから
I don't really understand you, but
clearly you must have a sensitive soul.
よくわかりませんが
きっと羽瀬川君は感情性が豊なのですね
You really are a perfect boyfriend
さすがリア充完璧超人柏崎星奈にぴったりのパーフェクトな彼氏さんです
to match the inhumanly perfect
real-lifer Kashiwazaki Sena!
I told you, I'm not her boyfriend!
We're just clubmates.
だから彼氏じゃねえよ　ただの部活仲間だ
Clubmates? But Kashiwazaki
Sena isn't in any clubs!
部活仲間　柏崎星奈は部活に入ってなかったはずです
The club started in June.
六月から始めたんだよ
"Neighbors Club"?
隣人部
I've never heard of that club.
What do you do in it?
聞いたことがない名前です
何をする部活なのですか
Um... Excuse me, I'm in a hurry!
えっと　すまん　ちょっと急いでるんだ
I apologize for delaying you.
お引止めしてすみませんでした
No prob. Good luck with your job too!
お前も仕事頑張れよ
Thank you!
はい
Infirmary
Rika, are you awake?
理科　起きてるか
Yes. Please feel free
to sneak into Rika's bed.
起きてますよ
夜這いも大歓迎です
Sheesh. That kind of joke is...
お前なあ
こういう冗談は
You should keep this cold forever.
お前　もうずっと風邪引いてろよ
Don't you think that was a little mean?
さすがにそれはひどいんじゃないですかね
Ah, sorry! I'm joking.
すまん　冗談だ
So the screenings are canceled?
上映会中止ですか
Yeah.
Rika was almost finished...
もうすこしで完成だったんですが
There's no point if
you're just gonna faint again.
それでまたお前が倒れたら意味ねぇだろう
Well, couldn't we screen
a 95% finished version?!
それじゃ95％くらい完成したバージョンを上映するとか
Not a chance, idiot.
それも駄目だ　馬鹿
Yozora says it's pointless if all
seven of us aren't at the first viewing.
最初は七人で見ないと意味がないんだってさ 夜空が
Yozora-sempai said that?
夜空先輩が
Yeah. Yozora said that!
あの夜空がだ
And I... We agreed with her.
俺も　俺達もそう思った
Gonna be moved to tears?
感動して泣いちゃうか
R-R-Rika's not crying!
な　泣いてないし
FYI, I almost cried.
ちなみに俺は泣きそうになったぞ
Rika is suddenly sleepy!
なんか眠くなっちゃいました
Kodaka-sempai.
小鷹先輩
If you want to molest Rika, now is the time.
もし理科に乱暴するなら今ですよ
Like in an ero-doujinshi.
エロ同人みたいに
Look, you. Do you even have a plan
for if I actually took you up on that?
お前なあ
それでもし俺が本当にそうしたらどうするつもりなんだよ
You never would, though.
でも　先輩はしないでしょう
Oh, Sempai! Since you're here, would
you read to Rika until she falls asleep?
先輩　せっかくですから
理科が眠るまで本を読んでくれませんか
Read?
本
This one, please!
これお願いします
"Secret Sessions with a Devil of a Teacher"
Th-That's a BL book!
BL本じゃねえか
Please read it, Sempai!
読んでくださいよ　先輩
Be serious.
あのな
This stuff is perfect for right now.
ちょうどいいんですよ　こういうのが
Okay, okay. You really are a
pervert, you know. Totally depraved.
わかったよ　お前は本当に変態だな
腐ってあがる
Thank you very much! Please
start with the bookmarked page!
ありがとうございます
ではそのしおりの挟んであるページから
"H-Heh... H-Heh, heh... Osawa-kun,
you look like you w-w-want it bad..."
フ　フフフ　大沢君も物欲しそうな顔ですね
"Is this how desperate you've
been for my d-d-di... ck?"
そんなにも私のに　にく…
もっと大きい声で
Rika can't hear you!
"F-For my dick?"!
肉棒が欲しかったのですか
Say it with feeling!
もっと気持ち込めて
"T-Teacher, please, put your
h-hot rod into my y-yaoi hole..."
先生　早く先生の熱いそれを
僕の　や　やおい穴に
Yaoi hole? What's a "yaoi hole"?
やおい穴　なんだよ　やおい穴って
What? You're a boy, and you
don't know about the yaoi hole?
男のくせに　やおい穴を知らないんですか
Huh?
What are you talking about?
何言ってんのお前
Hole?
Rika can't believe the
yaoi hole doesn't really exist...
まさかやおい穴が実在しないなんて
Why would you think it did?
するわけねえだろう
It's not Rika's fault! She's never
seen a boy naked in real life.
だってしょうがないじゃないですか
本物の男性の体なんて見たことないんですから
And she has no friends to correct her mistake...
間違いを訂正してくれる友達もいなかったんですから
But are you sure you don't
have one? Allow Rika to check...
ていうか本当にないんですか
ちょっと確認させ…
Just go to sleep! I'm heading out.
いいから寝ろ　俺はもう行くぞ
Okay.
はい
It's thanks to the Neighbors Club that we
can be silly with each other like this, huh?
お前とこうして馬鹿なことを喋ってられるのも 隣人部があったからだよな
Shiguma Rika
To the Neighbors Club.
The movie is finished, so please
come to the club room.
"To the Neighbors Club.
隣人部の皆さんへ
The movie is finished,
so please come to the club room."
映画が完成したので部室に来てください
Ahem. Rika sincerely apologizes
for all the inconvenience she caused.
今回は理科のせいでご迷惑をかけして大変申し訳ありませんでした
Hmph! I-It wasn't really...
別に
理科殿　お気になさらず
Please don't worry about it, Rika-dono.
いいから早く見せなさいよ
Wh-Whatever, just show us the movie.
私も早く映画を見たいぞ
I wanna see it now too!
くくく　見せてもらおうか　人間共の悪足掻きを
Let's see your fruitless human efforts.
All right, here we go.
それでは始めますよ
"The Legend of the Great Kasi Vazwakii Swena
~Love Is Life Is Found in Death~"
"Guilty"
And so the curtain closed on the
Neighbors Club's school festival.
こうして隣人部の学園祭は　幕を閉じたのだった
Real-lifer
King Real
Thumbs ready... two!
Thumbs ready... zero!
Thumbs ready... eight!
Please, behave yourselves!
いい加減にしてください
Oh, dear!
ハイスコアは更新
I beat my high score!
Who's she?
誰
I'm Yusa! Yusa Aoi! We're in the same class!
遊佐です　あなたと同じクラスの遊佐葵です
同じクラス
The same class?
We've had plenty of
conversations in the classroom!
教室で何度もお話ししてますよ
Now that you mention it,
I kind of feel like that's true...
言われてみれば見覚えがあるような
K-Kashiwazaki Sena,
you're mocking me again!
柏崎星奈
またそんなふうに自分を愚弄して
Look, don't take it too personally.
So, what brings you here?
まあ　あんまり気にするなって
ってか　何か用なのか
Oh, that's right!
そ　そうでした
Okay.
What is wrong with this club?!
All you ever do is play!
何なんですか　この部活は
遊んでばっかりじゃないですか
今はたまたま休憩していただけだ
We just happen to be taking a break right now.
I-It's no use lying! I've kept
tabs on you for some time now!
嘘をついても無駄です
自分はずっとあなた達を監視していたのです
Tabs?
監視
I got curious about what kind of
club you and Kashiwazaki Sena were in.
羽瀬川君や柏崎星奈が所属している部活が
どんなのか気になったのです
I-I see...
そ　そうだったのか
And? Supposing we did play all
the time, would that be a problem?
で　私達がこの部室で遊んでばかりいたとして
何が問題があるのか
部活にはそれぞれの活動方針がある
Each club has its own activity program.
部外者に口出しされるいわれはない
Outsiders have no right to stick their noses in.
自分は生徒会役員です
I am on the student council!
生徒会には道を踏み外した生徒を正す義務があります
Council members have a duty to
correct students who stray from the path!
なんつうか　遊佐は星奈をライバル視してて
Yusa thinks of Sena as a rival or
something. I think that's why she's here.
多分その流れで
っちぇ　肉のせいか
So this is Meat's fault?
The Neighbors Club is
officially recognized by the school,
隣人部とは学校に認められた部であり
and we abide by its stated aims.
我々はその活動目的に従っている
In compliance with God's instructions,
神の教えに則り
同じ学校に通う仲間の良き隣人となり
we become neighbors with our
fellow students, deepen that friendship,
友誼を深めるべく
誠心誠意臨機応変に切磋琢磨する
and, as occasion may require,
sincerely work hard together.
In other words, what appears
to be mere playing around
つまり
遊んでいるように見えるのは立派な隣人部の活動なのだ
is in fact perfectly legitimate club business!
Huh?
I'm amazed she remembers that spiel.
よく覚えてるな
We play video games and read
ゲームをするのも　読書をするのも
全ては同じ学校に通う仲間の良き隣人となるためだ
in order to become good
neighbors to our fellow students.
You want some too, don't you?
Fun friends. Knowledgeable friends.
貴様もほしいだろう
面白い友達
知識が豊富な友達
Friends who share your
interests. Dependable friends.
趣味が合う友達
頼りになる友達
I want some!
ほしい
Shut up.
黙れ
We work hard together each day in
our quest to be magnificent neighbors.
私達はそんな素晴らしい隣人になることを目指し
日々切磋琢磨しているのだ
た　確かに　そうした友人の存在は人生を豊にしてくれると思います
T-True, I believe such friends
would enrich a person's life.
But you didn't seem to be doing that at all!
でも　とてもそんなふうには見えませんでした
That's your personal impression.
それは貴様の主観だろう
Does the council reject the activities of law-abiding
students based on personal impressions?
生徒会は主観で善良な一般生徒の活動を否定するのか
But what about that girl?!
でも　そこの人とか
Or that one?!
あと　あの人とか
I don't think it's right to break school rules!
校則違反をするのはよくないと思います
School rules?
校則違反
服装です
Look at their clothes! According
to Student Handbook Article 5,
生徒心得五条　服装に関する規定により
the Rules for Attire, " Students
are required to wear their uniforms
本学園の生徒は登校下校及び　校内においては
while on campus as well as
on their way to and from sch..."
学園規定の制服を着用することが義務つけられて
Article 5 Section 4 stipulates
the exceptions to that rule.
五条四項に制服着用義務の例外が定められている
I believe club activities
are specifically included.
部活同時もそこに含まれると明記されているはずだ
F-Four... You're right.
四　四
確かに
But these exceptions are for
gym clothes and other uniforms...
ですが　ここで規定されているのは体操着やユニホームのことで
If so, you should fill
out the official paperwork
なら校則改定手続きを取って
to have the handbook amended to clarify that.
そう明記されるよう変えることだな
くくく　我は人間の定めた法理など縛られぬ
I am not bound by human laws.
That's because you're in middle school.
それお前は中等部だからな
Middle school? What's a middle
school student doing in this club?!
中等部
中等部の子がどうして部員になっているのですか
There's no rule stating that
middle schoolers can't be club members.
中等部の生徒を部員にしてはいけないという規定はない
Outsiders aren't allowed inside
school buildings without permission!
部外者が許可なく校舎内立ち入ることは禁止されています
True, perhaps it is against the
rules to allow outsiders into a club.
確かに部外者を入部させるのは校則違反かもしれないな
Exactly!
でしょう
But are the middle schoolers "outsiders"?
だが　中等部の生徒は部外者か
Though in a different school, they are
nevertheless students of St. Chronica's Academy.
中等部とは言え
れっきとした聖クロニカ学園所属する学生であり
Moreover, is it reasonable to
call our blood relatives "outsiders"?
しかも部員の血縁者を部外者とするのは無理があるのではないか
Furthermore, this chapel
may be on school grounds,
さらにこの礼拝堂は学園の敷地内に建ってはいるが
but it is open to the public.
一般開放されている施設でもある
Therefore, there is no problem
with Hasegawa Kodaka's sister
よって羽瀬川小鷹の妹が部員としてここにいることに何の問題もない
being here as a club member!
You heard her.
だってさ
Good for you, huh?
よかったな
Grrrrr... Th-This isn't over!
覚えておいてください
Okay.
Hmph! And stay out, student council dog.
二度と来るな　生徒会の犬目
Conversations with
strangers make me nervous...
知らない人間と会話するのは緊張する
Good work, club president.
お疲れさん　部長
I have you this time!
今日こそ観念してもらいます
またお前か
You again?
Y-Your confidence is about to end!
その余裕もここまでです
I've found a definitive reason why the
Neighbors Club isn't a legitimate club!
隣人部が正式な部として求められない決定的な理由を見つけました
More crazy talk.
また妄言を
Section 2 of the Rules
for Extracurricular Activities:
学校外の活動に関する規定二項
"As a rule, classes, clubs, and
other activities undertaken in groups
クラスクラブ等の団体での活動については
関係教官の引率がない場合 原則としてこれを認めない
must be conducted under
the supervision of an instructor"!
要するに部活には顧問が必要ってことだろう
That just means clubs
have to have advisors, right?
And your advisor is the issue here!
その顧問が問題なのです
Article 78 of the Student Council bylaws
生徒会会則七十八条
states that "Club advisors must
be faculty or staff of this school"!
クラブの顧問は本校に勤務する教官または職員であること
Per Section 2, a sister's
rights and responsibilities
規定二項において　シスターの権利と義務は教官のそれに順ずるものとある
are equivalent to those of the faculty.
There's no problem here.
何の問題もない
Yes, if your adviser were a
sister, there would be no problem.
確かに　シスターが顧問なら問題はありません
However, Takayama Maria
over there is not a sister!
ですが　そこにいる高山マリアさんは
シスターではありません
There is no "Takayama Maria" on the
list of sisters assigned to this school!
学園に派遣されているシスターの名簿に
「高山マリア」という名前はありません
Only her older sister Kate-sensei is listed!
記載されているのは姉のケイト先生の名前のみ
In other words, she's just a
little girl who hangs out in the chapel!
つまり彼女は礼拝堂に出入りしているだけのただの幼女なのです
だ　だが　創部届けは問題なく受理されたぞ
B-But the club application was approved!
Merely a mistake!
それはただのミスです
ちょっと待ってくれ
H-Hold on a sec!
Big Brother? What's wrong?
お兄ちゃん　どうしたの
I want to ask you something...
Isn't Maria a sister?
聞きたいことがあって
マリアってさ　シスターじゃないのか
Nope.
What, just like that?!
そんなあっさり
I'm having her act as my assistant,
partly to learn about the real world.
社会勉強も兼ねて私の手伝いをさせているのさ
After all, if she's at my school,
I can keep an eye on her.
同じ学校にいれば私の目もちゃんと届くからね
Then why does Maria call herself "sensei"?
マリアが自分のこと　先生って言ってるのは
Oh, that's just something she says!
あいつが勝手に言ってるだけだよ
So why does she wear nun's robes?!
じゃなんでシスター服を着てるんだ
Because it's cute!
可愛いからさ
Takayama Kate
マジでシスターじゃないらしい
Apparently she really isn't a sister.
Oh... So I'm not a sister after all...
そっか
私はシスターじゃなかったか
I wonder what I am, then...
私って一体何なんだろうな
A-Anyway, since you don't have an advisor,
とにかく顧問がいない以上
正式な部として認められません
you can't be recognized as a legitimate club!
不正な手段で作られた部として廃部の処分もあり得るでしょう
As a club formed under false
pretenses, you could be disbanded!
それがいやなら今後はもって…
If you don't want that, then
from now on you'd better...
If Maria's an official
advisor, we're good, right?
マリアが正式な顧問ならいいのよね
Y-Yes, but... The issue
is that she's not, so...
そうですけど
そうでないから駄目なわけ
Uh-huh. Wait here a second.
じゃあちょっと待ってて
Anybody want some coffee?
コーヒーでも飲むか
Huh?
Don't worry; it's not poisoned.
心配すんな　毒なんか入ってないから
I'm afraid I've carelessly missed
a chance to eliminate the enemy.
わたくしとしたことが　敵を排除する好機を逃してしまいました
Eliminating her really isn't necessary.
いや　排除しなくていいから
待たせたわね　愚民共
Thank you for waiting, commoners.
Maria's been offered a position
as a special part-time instructor.
マリアが特別非常勤講師に内定したわ
Huh?
What's a "special part-time instructor"?
特別非常勤講師って何なのだ
先生みたいなものよ
A teacher, basically.
パパに電話して相談したの
I called Daddy about our little problem.
Pardon?
I can be a real teacher?
わたし　本当の先生になれるのか
Yep. What do you say?
うん　どうする
なる　なります
Yes! I'll do it!
Okay. We'll put in the paperwork, then.
あっそう　それじゃ手続きするわ
- Yay! Yay! I'm gonna be a real teacher!
- Daddy? About what we were talking about...
ふわふわ　わたし本当の先生になるぞ
パパ　さっきの件だけど
- Yay, yay!
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Thanks. Bye.
宜しくね　じゃあ
Yay!
This is preposterous!
こんなの無茶苦茶です
The school president made the
decision. Got a problem with that?
理事長が決めたのよ　文句ある
Of course I do!
あるに決まってます
そもそも今更正式な顧問を立てたところで
And getting a proper advisor now
不正な手段で作られた部という事実に変わり…
doesn't change the fact that
the club was created on false...
Silence, mongrel.
黙りなさい　駄犬
Just so you know, even if the
student council calls for our disbandment,
言っとくけどね
たとえ生徒会が廃部を申し立てようが
I can get that proposal canned.
握り潰すことも出来るの
I got us an advisor for you so
that you don't look like a fool later.
あんたの顔を潰さないよう
ちゃんと顧問を立ててあげたのよ
Be grateful.
感謝しなさい
I-I don't accept that!
そんなの　自分は認めません
Listen closely, mongrel!
よく聞きなさい　駄犬
This club belongs to me.
If you keep barking on my turf...
この部はあたしのものなの
もしあたしの庭でこれ以上うるさく吠えるようなら
...I'll crush you.
捻り潰すわよ
退学にでもしてあげようかしら
How about I get you expelled, hmm?
Y-You can't do th...
そんなことできるわけ…
出来ないと思うのはあんたの自由よ
You just keep telling yourself that.
お騒がせして　すみませんでした
P-Please pardon my intrusion.
A rich girl who abuses her influence
to crush underfoot all who defy her...
権力を盾にはむかう者を叩き潰すお嬢様
まるっきり悪役だな
You're a total villain.
手っ取り早く解決できたんだからいいじゃない
I got rid of her quick, so what's the problem?
No! I missed Kaoru-chan in
her bunny ears and white bikini!
薫ちゃんのウサギ耳白ビギニが
Wait, did you resort to threats to run her off
まさか早くゲームをやりたくてあの人を追い払ったんですか
just so you could get back to your game?!
脅しまで
Naturally!
あったりまえじゃない
Sena-anego's principles are unwavering.
星奈の姉御は揺るぎないですね
Eh, if flaunting a little power
権力をちらつかせるだけでどうにかなる相手なんてどうでもいいのよ
is enough to get rid of her,
she's not worth my time.
Someone with an actual spine
would ignore it and keep coming at me.
本当に骨のあるやつはそんなのおかまいなしに向かってくるんだから
I feel a little bad for Yusa, but...
遊佐には少し悪いことをしたが
With these two around, the
Neighbors Club is safe from any challengers.
この二人がいれば
誰が来ても隣人部は安泰だな
Oh, hey, Kodaka.
そういえば　小鷹
Hmm?
This came up while I was
on the phone with Daddy...
さっきパパと電話した時に話題になったんだけど
Yeah?
- Oh, dear!
Marry me after all.
あんたやっぱりあたしと結婚しなさいよ
I've been thinking about it
ever since the betrothal thing.
この間からずっと考えてたんだけど
I've said this before: I don't care
about some promise between our fathers.
前にも言ったじゃない
パパとあんたのお父さんとの約束なんてどうでもいいのよ
But it's that promise that I don't care about.
でもこの「どうでもいい」ってのは　約束それ自体のことで
When we discovered the engagement,
なんか婚約が発覚した時は 結婚そのものがなしみたいになっちゃったけど
the wedding itself ended up
called off, but this is a separate issue.
それとは関係なしに
今のあたしの気持ち的には　あんたと結婚したいと思うのよ
My feelings right now
are that I want to marry you.
だってあたし
I mean, I love you and everything.
小鷹のことが好きだから
Hmm?! What did you say?!
ええ　何だって
Ugh, you made me screw up, idiot!
もう　ミスしちゃったじゃない　馬鹿
O-Oh, sorry. So, what did you say?
すまん　何だって
何だってじゃない
"What did you say," my butt!
Huh, I-I guess I said it.
そっか　言っちゃった
Well, that's okay. I was
planning to tell you sooner or later.
まあいいか　どうせそのうち言うつもりだったし
Um, so basically...
えっとね　つまり　何か そういうことだから
That's the deal, okay?
Wh-What's the deal with what?
The game was so loud, I couldn't hear you.
何が「そういうことなんだ」
ゲームの音が大きくて　何も聞こえなかったな
Kodaka?
小鷹
I-I just remembered something I have to do!
そういえば　急用思い出した
光ったはずの星
A stray cloud blocks my view
Of the star I know should be shining there
迷った雲が邪魔して
見えなくなる
What should I believe in?
何を信じたらいい
I was on my way to breaking
不安定すぎる世界で
The treasure bred in this all too changeable world
育った宝物壊しかけてた
Because I was afraid of losing it
なくすのが怖くて
不条理だって
Those days of sighing "This is absurd"
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
And flailing inside my birdcage
We were gazing up at the same sky
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
When I gripped your hand,
you gripped back, didn't you?
君の手を握った時
握り返してくれたね
These joined hands are stronger than any wings
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
We can fly higher even without wings
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
So I know we'll be okay trying now
きっと今なら大丈夫
Let's grab the stars twinkling in the sky
大空輝く星を掴もう
Demon Astaroth!
魔人アシタロス
Today is the day I'll use the
magic passed on to me by my teacher
師匠から受け継いだこの魔法で
今日こそあなたを完全に滅ぼす
to destroy you forever!
You've got spirit, Guernica.
威勢がいいの　ゲルニカよ
But first let me tell
you this: I am your father!
だがその前に教えてやろう
実はわしは　お前の父だ
What? A horse like you?! How?!
どうしてあなたのような　馬が
It's a long story.
話せば長くなる
Never mind, then.
じゃあいいです
W-Wait! Just one thing, then...
ま　待って　では一つだけ
"I ______ Many Friends"
Next time, the final episode of
Haganai Next: "I ______ Many Friends."
次回
はがないネクスト最終話　「僕は友達が…」
Shatter the very soul of
my enemy! Nine Lives Breaker!
魂ごと打ち砕け
ナインダイブスブレイカー